investigator.co.ug 2016-03-18

# Privacy – The Investigator

**Your Privacy**

The Investigator is committed to protecting you and your family’s personal information. We want our services to be safe and enjoyable environments for everyone. This site aims to help you to understand what information we might collect about you and how we use it. 

  1. **Introduction & General Terms**

The Investigator is committed to protecting your and your family’s personal information when you are using our services. We want our services to be safe and enjoyable environments for our audience. This Privacy Policy relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us via phone or text, by email, inboxes, in letters or correspondence. 

It also relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us online, or on mobile. In order to provide you with the full range of Investigator services, we sometimes need to collect information about you. 

**This Privacy Policy explains the following:**

What information the INVESTIGATOR may collect about you; 

How the INVESTIGATOR will use information collected about you; 

When the INVESTIGATOR may use your details to contact you; 

Whether the INVESTIGATOR will disclose your details to anyone else; 

Your choices regarding the personal information you provide to us; 

The use of cookies on INVESTIGATOR websites and how you can reject these cookies. 

The INVESTIGATOR is committed to safeguarding your personal information. Whenever you provide such information, we are legally obliged to use your information in line with all laws concerning the protection of personal information, including the Data Protection Act 1998 (these laws are referred to collectively in this Privacy Policy as the “data protection laws”). 

INVESTIGATOR websites contain hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third party websites have their own privacy policies, and are also likely to use cookies, and we therefore urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit, which may also be collected by cookies whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at own risk. 

  2. **Who are we?**

The INVESTIGATOR is an Online Publication Company in Uganda. We are a private service provider. 

The INVESTIGATOR reports majorly about Local News, Business News, Sports News, Politics, Health, Tourism and Crime news among others. 

  3. **What information will the INVESTIGATOR collect about me?**

When you participate in, access or sign up to any of the INVESTIGATOR’s services, activities or online content, such as newsletters, competitions, live chats, message boards, telephone or text the INVESTIGATOR, vote, donate money to a INVESTIGATOR charity appeal, book tickets for an INVESTIGATOR event or create an account using the INVESTIGATOR’s online registration system we may receive personal information about you. This can consist of information such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone or mobile number or date of birth, depending on the activity. 

By submitting your details, you enable the INVESTIGATOR (and where applicable its contractors) to provide you with the services, activities or online content you select. 

  4. **How will the INVESTIGATOR use the information it collects about me?**

The INVESTIGATOR will use your personal information for a number of purposes including the following: 

To provide our services or online content and to deal with your requests and enquiries; for “service administration purposes,” which means that the INVESTIGATOR may contact you for reasons related to the service, activity or online content you have signed up for, as set out in section 5 below (e.g. to provide you with password reminders or to notify you that a particular service, activity or online content has been suspended for maintenance); 

To contact you about a submission you have made, including any content you provide. 

To provide you with information about our services, activities or online content; 

To analyze and improve the services offered on INVESTIGATOR websites; 

To provide you, with the most user-friendly navigation experience. The INVESTIGATOR may also use and disclose information in aggregate (so that no individuals are identified) for marketing and strategic development purposes; and 

Where the INVESTIGATOR proposes using your personal information for any other uses, we will ensure that we notify you or seek your consent first. You will also be given the opportunity to withhold or withdraw your consent for the use of your personal information for purposes other than those listed above. 

  5. **When will the INVESTIGATOR contact me?**

The INVESTIGATOR may contact you: 

In relation to any service, activity or online content you have signed up for in order to ensure that the INVESTIGATOR can deliver the services to you; 

In relation to any correspondence we receive from you or any comment or complaint you make about INVESTIGATOR products or services; 

In relation to any contribution you have submitted to the INVESTIGATOR, e.g. on the INVESTIGATOR message boards or via text or voicemail message; 

To invite you to participate in surveys about the INVESTIGATOR services (participation is always voluntary); and, For marketing purposes, where you have agreed to this (see section 6 below) 

Local pages will give you detailed information about how the INVESTIGATOR will contact you in relation to specific services, activities or online content. 

  6. **Will I be contacted for marketing purposes?**

The INVESTIGATOR will only use your information for marketing purposes, or to promote new services, activities or online content where you have agreed to this. 

  7. **Will the INVESTIGATOR share my personal information with anyone else?**

We will keep your information confidential except where disclosure is required or permitted by law (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies) or as described in section 8 below. Generally, we will only use your information within the INVESTIGATOR. However, sometimes the INVESTIGATOR uses third parties to process your information on our behalf. The INVESTIGATOR requires these third parties to comply strictly with its instructions and the INVESTIGATOR requires that they do not use your personal information for their own business purposes, unless you have explicitly consented to the use of your personal information in this way. 

  8. **Offensive or inappropriate content on INVESTIGATOR websites**

If you post or send offensive, inappropriate or objectionable content anywhere on or to INVESTIGATOR websites or otherwise engage in any disruptive behavior on any INVESTIGATOR service, the INVESTIGATOR may use your personal information to stop such behavior. 

Where the INVESTIGATOR reasonably believes that you are or may be in breach of any applicable laws (e.g. because content you have posted may be defamatory), the INVESTIGATOR may use your personal information to inform relevant third parties such as your employer, school email/internet provider or law enforcement agencies about the content and your behavior. 

  9. **What if I am a user aged 18 or under?**

If you are aged 18 or under, please get your parent/guardian’s permission before you provide any personal information to the INVESTIGATOR. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information. 

  1. **How long will the INVESTIGATOR keep my personal information?**

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with the INVESTIGATOR or the INVESTIGATOR’s corporate retention schedule (a database that defines which documents should be kept and for how long). If you cancel your registration as an INVESTIGATOR website member and your account is deleted a red flag goes on the database and, while the INVESTIGATOR cannot use the personal information, it stays on the system for a period of one year for administration purposes before being deleted automatically. 

Where you contribute material to the INVESTIGATOR we will generally only keep your content for as long as is reasonably required for the purpose(s) for which it was submitted. For example, we will only keep copies of entries to a photographic competition for the duration of the competition. 

  1. **Can I find out what personal information the INVESTIGATOR holds about me?**

Under the Data Protection Act you have the right to request a copy of the personal information the INVESTIGATOR holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. 

Please address requests and questions about this or any other question about this Privacy Policy to the Data Team by sending email to [info@investigator.co.ug](mailto:info@investigator.co.ug)

  2. **What if I am accessing INVESTIGATOR websites outside the Uganda?**

The INVESTIGATOR website is published in UGANDA by the INVESTIGATOR as Investigator.co.ug All personal information submitted by users outside the UGANDA to Investigator.com will be processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy (and any local terms that apply to certain areas of the site). Where there is a conflict, the local terms will apply. 

  3. **Cookies Policy – Information the INVESTIGATOR collects from you**

a. What is a cookie? 

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your computer, tablet or mobile phone (referred to here as a “device”) browser from a website’s computer and is stored on your device’s hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other websites. Many websites do this whenever a user visits their website in order to track online traffic flows. 

On INVESTIGATOR websites, cookies record information about your online preferences and allow us to tailor our websites to your interests. 

During the course of any visit to the INVESTIGATOR website, the pages you see, along with a cookie, are downloaded to your device. Many websites do this, because cookies enable website publishers to do useful things like find out whether the device (and probably its user) has visited the website before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit. 

  1. **How does the INVESTIGATOR use cookies?**

Information supplied by cookies can help us to analyse the profile of our visitors and help us to provide you with a better user experience. For example, if on a previous visit you went to our education pages, we might find this out from your cookie and highlight educational information on your second and subsequent visits. The INVESTIGATOR uses this type of information to help improve the services it provides to its users. All third parties are strictly required not to use any information for their own business or other purposes (see section 6 above). Certain areas of INVESTIGATOR websites may use cookies for a specific reason – for example, to help an online game work effectively on your device. 

  1. **Third Party Cookies in embedded content on INVESTIGATOR pages**

Please note that during your visits to INVESTIGATOR websites you may notice some cookies that are not related to the INVESTIGATOR or the INVESTIGATOR’s contractors. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. The INVESTIGATOR does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the third party websites for more information about these. 

  4. **Do Not Track (DNT) browser setting**

DNT is a feature offered by some browsers which, when enabled, sends a signal to websites to request that your browsing is not tracked, such as by third party ad networks, social networks and analytic companies. This website does not currently respond to DNT requests, however, you may opt-out of tracking on this website, including analytics (and tailored advertising if you are visiting from outside UGANDA), by changing your cookie settings. 

A uniform standard has not yet been adopted to determine how DNT requests should be interpreted and what actions should be taken by websites and third parties. The INVESTIGATOR will continue to review DNT and other new technologies and may adopt a DNT standard once available. 

  5. **Changes to INVESTIGATOR’s Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time so you may wish to check it each time you submit personal information to the INVESTIGATOR. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page. If you do not agree to these changes, please do not continue to use INVESTIGATOR websites to submit personal information to the INVESTIGATOR. If material changes are made to the Privacy Policy we will notify you by placing a prominent notice on the website. 

  7. **Contacting the INVESTIGATOR about this Privacy Policy**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy please contact: 

The Data Protection Team 

Raja Chambers, RM FA 057, Parliamentary Avenue, 

P.O.Box 3093, Kampala, Uganda 

Email: info@investigator.co.ug 

Tel: (+256)755 430 145/701 120 000 

### [The Investigator News](http://theinvestigatornews.com/author/the-investigator/ "The Investigator News")

The Investigator is Uganda’s First Online News Daily with the Latest in Crime, Politics, Business, Entertainment, Sports, Job Opportunities, Opinions and Analysis. We bring you with the Latest Breaking News on your Mobile and Desktop. [More Than Just News]

[More Posts](http://theinvestigatornews.com/author/the-investigator/ "More posts by The Investigator News") \- [Website](http://www.investigator.co.ug/ "The Investigator News")

Follow Me:
